MSc

Departmento de Ecologia, Instituto de Biosciências, Universidade de São Paulo

#### □+5511991218851 | ▼francisco.albertas@gmail.com | ♥ FdAlbertas

About me\_

Biologist with a Master and an ongoing Ph.D. in Ecology – to be concluded in January 2021 – with 10 years' experience working with applied research focusing on understanding how the spatial pattern of human-modified land-scapes affects biodiversity, ecosystem services provision and the Climate.

## Skills\_\_\_\_\_

R - MARKDOWN - GIS - DATA ANALYSIS - ECOSYSTEM SERVICE MODELLING - ENVIRONMENTAL RESTORATION - WRITING AND COMMUNICATION - GOOGLE EARTH ENGINE

## Languages \_\_\_\_

PORTUGUESE (NATIVE) - ENGLISH (FLUENT) - FRENCH (ADVANCED) - SPANISH (INTERMEDIATE)

### Education

Universidade de São Paulo São Paulo

PHD IN ECOLOGY 2017-202

Universidade de São Paulo São Paulo, Brasil

MASTER IN ECOLOGY 2013-2015

Universidade de São Paulo São Paulo

BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES DEGREE 2006-2011

# Professional experiences \_\_\_\_\_

World Wildlife Fund - WWF Brazil São Paulo, Brasil

CONSULTANCY - MONITORING DEFORESTATION AND FIRE WITHIN AMAZONIA AND CERRADO PROTECTED AREAS

2020-202

Instituto Socioambiental - ISA São Paulo, Brasil

CONSULTANCY - MAPPING THREATS TO FEDERAL AND STATE PROTECTED AREAS IN BRAZIL 2017-2018

Klabin s/a Papel e Celulose Paraná, Brasil

Consultancy - Planning ecological corridors between indigenous lands 2016

Bloomberg Philanthropies e Global Road Safety
São Paulo, Brasil

CONSULTANCY - FLORISTIC INVENTORY OF URBAN AREAS IN SAO PAULO 2016

Instituto Socioambiental - ISA São Paulo, Brasil

JUNIOR ENVIRONMENTAL ANALYST (INTERNSHIP) - PROTECTED AREAS MONITORING PROGRAME 2012-2013

Mineral Engenharia e Ambiente São Paulo, Brasil

JUNIOR ENVIRONMENTAL ANALYST (INTERNSHIP) - OIL AND MINING ENVIRONMENTAL IMPACT EVALUATION 2011-2012

# **Research** experience

#### **University of Cambridge**

VISITING RESEARCHER - COLABORATION WITH ANDREW BALMFORD'S GROUP (CONSERVATION SCIENCE GROUP)

Cambridge, United Kingdom

2020-202

Laboratório de Ecologia da Paisagem e Conservação-LEPaC(Departmento de Ecologia, Universidade de São Paulo)

São Paulo, Brasil

RESEARCH TECHNICIAN - SAO PAULO RESEARCH FOUNDATION TRAINING SCHOLARSHIP TO BE PART OF THE BIODIVERSITY AND ECOSYSTEM SERVICE SCENARIOS NETWORK (SCENNET)

2015-2017

### **Publications**

**d'Albertas, F.**, González-Chaves, A., Borges-Matos, C., Zago de Almeida Paciello, V., Maron, M., Metzger, J.P., 2021. Private reserves suffer from the same location biases of public protected areas. Biological Conservation 261, 109283. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biocon.2021.109283

Helena Fany Pantaleoni RIcardo; Alicia Rolla; Silvia Futada; **Francisco d'Albertas G. de Carvalho**. 2019. O estado das áreas protegifas: Garimpo ilegal nas UCs e TIs da Amazônia Brasileira. https://bit.ly/3sIxequ

Acosta, A.L., **d'Albertas, F.**, Leite, M. de S., Saraiva, A.M., Metzger, J.P.W., 2018. Gaps and limitations in the use of restoration scenarios: a review. Restoration Ecology 26, 1108–1119. https://doi.org/10.1111/rec.12882

**d'Albertas, F.**, Costa, K., Romitelli, I., Barbosa, J.M., Vieira, S.A., Metzger, J.P., 2018. Lack of evidence of edge age and additive edge effects on carbon stocks in a tropical forest. Forest Ecology and Management 407, 57–65. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foreco.2017.09.042

Metzger, J.P., Esler, K., Krug, C., Arias, M., Tambosi, L., Crouzeilles, R., Acosta, A.L., Brancalion, P.H., **d'Albertas, F.**, Duarte, G.T., Garcia, L.C., Grytnes, J.-A., Hagen, D., Jardim, A.V.F., Kamiyama, C., Latawiec, A.E., Rodrigues, R.R., Ruggiero, P.G., Sparovek, G., Strassburg, B., Saraiva, A.M., Joly, C., 2017. Best practice for the use of scenarios for restoration planning. Current Opinion in Environmental Sustainability, Part A: Environmental change issues • Part B: Open Issue, Part III 29, 14–25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cosust.2017.10.004

**d'Albertas, F.**, Pinto, L.F.G., Sparovek, G., Metzger. J.P. In which situations ecological restoration can contribute with agricultural productivity? In preparation.

**d'Albertas, F.**, Ruggiero, P., Pinto, L.F.G., Sparovek, G., Metzger, J.P. Before-after control evaluation of agricultural certification schemes. In preparation.